Inventory of the Russian subject collection
Hoover Institution Archives
Russian subject collection
1700-2016
XX743
Hoover Institution Archives
59 manuscript boxes, 13 oversize boxes, 1 oversize folder, 10 videocassettes, 16 sound tape reels, 2 sound cassettes, 8 sound discs, memorabilia (41.8 linear feet)
Pamphlets, leaflets, serial issues, clippings, other printed matter, correspondence, memoranda, reports, orders, translations, election campaign literature, video and sound recordings, and memorabilia relating to political, social, and economic conditions in Russia, and in the Russian empire as a whole, the Soviet Union as a whole, and the Soviet successor states collectively, and especially to the Russian Revolution and Civil War, American engineers in Russia, and post-1991 elections in Russia.
Access
The collection is open for research.
Use copies of some video and sound recordings are available for immediate access. To listen to other sound recordings or to view other videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Content of Collection
Pamphlets, leaflets, serial issues, clippings, other printed matter, correspondence, memoranda, reports, orders, translations, election campaign literature, video and sound recordings, and memorabilia relating to political, social, and economic conditions in Russia, and in the Russian empire as a whole, the Soviet Union as a whole, and the Soviet successor states collectively, and especially to the Russian Revolution and Civil War, American engineers in Russia, and post-1991 elections in Russia. Video use copies of videocassette available.
Engineering--Soviet Union.; Soviet Union--History.; Soviet Union--History--Revolution, 1917-1921.; Russia--History.; Elections--Russia (Federation); Former Soviet republics.; Engineers.; Sound recordings.; Video tapes.; Audiotapes.
- Subject File (Boxes 1-26, 28)
  - Pre-revolutionary period
    - Commerce. Chembers, A. Ia., "Razvitie russkoi torgovli za poslednie pered revoliutsiei 25 let," Lektsii o Rossii, undated (Box-folder 1: 1)
    - La Commission Extraordinaire d'Enquête Instituée par l'Ordre de Sa Majesté l'Empereur de Russie, 1914 (Box-folder 1: 2)
    - Departament Zheleznodorozhnykh Del, 1891-1909 (Box-folder 1: 3)
    - Gosudarstvennaia Kantseliariia, 1903-1909 (Box-folder 1: 4)
    - Gosudarstvennyi Sovet
      - 1888-1916 (Box-folder 1: 5)
      - 1907-1916 (Box-folder 1: 6)
    - Imperatorskaia Akademiia nauk, 1909-1910 (Box-folder 1: 7)
    - "Istoriia proiskhozhdeniia russkago gosudarstvennago obshchestvennogo poriadka,", undated (Box-folder 1: 8)
    - Laws and statutes
      - General, 1903-1910 (Box-folder 1: 9)
      - Inheritance laws, document relating to, 1904 (Box-folder 1: 10)
      - Osoboe Soveshchanie po peresmotru ustanovlennykh dlia okhrany gosudarstvennago poriadka iskliuchitel'nykh zakonopolozhenii, St. Petersburg, 1905 (Box-folder 1: 11)
    - Military [Russia. Armiia. Leib-Gvardii Kirasirskii Ego Velichestva Polk]. Correspondence, diaries, and printed matter, 1916-1974
      Scope and Contents note
      Relates to the activities of the Imperial Russian Life Guard Cuirassier Regiment of His Majesty before and during the Russian Revolution and civil war and to the activities of surviving members in foreign countries after their emigration from Russia. In Russian.
      - Activities of the regiment
        - 1921-1940 (Box-folder 1: 12)
        - 1922-1969 (Box-folder 2: 1)
        - 1931-1939 (Box-folder 2: 2)
        - 1952-1968 (Box-folder 2: 3)
      - Brazol', Cornet, diary, 1916-1920 (Box-folder 2: 4)
      - Cherkasskii, Igor M.
        - Correspondence, memoranda, orders, 1918-1920 (Box-folder 2: 5-6)
        - Diary, 1918-1919 (Box-folder 3: 1)
        - Field books, 1919 (Box-folder 3: 2)
        - "Grimasy grazhdanskoi voiny,", undated (Box-folder 3: 3)
        - Leib-Eskadron Kirasir Ego Velichestva v Grazhdanskoi voine,", 1921 (Box-folder 3: 4)
        - Military memoirs, 1920 (Box-folder 3: 5)
      - Correspondence
        - General
          - 1915-1916 (Box-folder 3: 6)
          - 1952 (Box-folder 3: 7)
        - Aleksandr Mikhailovich, Grand Duke, 1930 (Box-folder 3: 8)
        - Anastasiia Nikolaevna, Grand Duchess, 1929 (Box-folder 3: 9)
        - Andrei Vladimirovich, Grand Duke, 1938, 1943 (Box-folder 3: 10)
        - Boris Vladimirovich, Grand Duke, 1938, 1943 (Box-folder 3: 11)
        - Elena Vladimirovna, Grand Duchess, 1952 (Box-folder 3: 12)
        - Gavriil Konstantinovich, Grand Duke, 1934-1950 (Box-folder 3: 13)
        - Kseniia Aleksandrovna, Grand Duchess, 1934, 1939 (Box-folder 3: 14)
        - Kutepov, Aleksandr Pavlovich, General, 1928 (Box-folder 3: 15)
        - Mariia Feodorovna, Dowager Empress, 1923-1927 (Box-folder 3: 16)
        - Nikolai Nikolaevich, Grand Duke, 1924-1928 (Box-folder 3: 17)
        - Ol'denburgskii, Aleksandr, 1930-1932 (Box-folder 3: 18)
        - Ol'ga Aleksandrovna, Grand Duchess, 1939 (Box-folder 3: 19)
        - Vladimir Kirilovich, Grand Duke, 1939-1974 (Box-folder 3: 20)
        - Vrangel', Petr Nikolaevich, Baron, 1926 (Box-folder 3: 21)
      - Dnevnik Leib-Eskadrona v Dobrovol'cheskoi Armii, 1918-1920 (Box-folder 3: 22)
      - Goshtovt, Georgii
        - Kirasiry Ego Velichestva v Velikuiu Voinu, Paris, undated (Box-folder 3: 23)
        - Kirasiry Ego Velichestva v Velikuiu Voinu 1915 g., Paris, 1942 (Box-folder 4: 1)
        - Kirasiry Ego Velichestva v Velikuiu Voinu 1916, 1917 goda, Paris, undated (Box-folder 4: 2)
      - History of the regiment (Box-folder 4: 3-4)
      - Kirasiry Ego Velichestva, 1902-1914, undated (Box-folder 4: 5)
      - Kuchin, A. D., diary, 1919-1920 (Box-folder 4: 6)
      - Mariia Feodorovna, Dowager Empress, burial, 1928 October (Box-folder 4: 7)
      - Marriages of regiment members (Box-folder 4: 8)
      - Menus (Box-folder 4: 9)
      - Obituaries (Box-folder 4: 10)
      - Officer casualties during World War I (Box-folder 4: 11)
      - Rozenshil'd-Paulin, Poruchik, "Otkhod na Kuban',", undated (Box-folder 4: 12)
      - Uniforms, oversize album of reproductions of color drawings, 1872 (Box 22)
      - Ustav (Box-folder 4: 13)
      - "Vestnik Gvardeiskogo Ob'edineniia"
        - 1958-1959 (Box-folder 5: 1)
        - 1964-1966 (Box-folder 5: 2)
        - 1970 (Box-folder 5: 3)
      - Zhurnal 3-go Eskadrona, 1914-1915 (Box-folder 5: 4)
      - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 5: 5-6)
    - Ministries
      - Komitet Ministrov, "K voprosu ob ob'edinenii vysshago gosudarstvennago nachal'stva,", undated (Box-folder 5: 7)
      - Ministerstvo Finansov, 1909-1917 (Box-folder 5: 8)
      - Ministerstvo Narodnago Prosveshcheniia
        - Funds, 1908 (Box-folder 5: 9)
        - Industrial education plan, undated (Box-folder 5: 10)
        - Ustav real'nykh uchilishch, undated (Box-folder 5: 11)
      - Ministerstvo Putei Soobshcheniia, 1906-1913 (Box-folder 5: 12)
      - Ministerstvo Torgoli i Promyshlennosti, 1907-1911 (Box-folder 5: 13)
      - Ministerstvo Vnutrennikh Del, 1904-1907 (Box-folder 5: 14)
      - Ministerstvo Zemledeliia i Gosudarstvennykh Imushchestv, letter to S. Iu. Vitte from A. Ermolov, 1905 February 14 (Box-folder 5: 15)
      - Voennoe Ministerstvo, 1900-1910 (Box-folder 6: 1)
    - Moskovskii universitet, fiziko-matematicheskii fakul'tet, 1908 (Box-folder 6: 2)
    - Okhrana [Bint, Henri Jean]. Dossier of the Swiss police, 1903-1919 (Box-folder 6: 3)
      Relates to H. J. Bint, an agent of the Russian secret police.
    - Pravitel'stvuiushchii senat, stat'ia 44 i 85 nakaz, April 12, 1907, Okhrana (secret police) (Box-folder 6: 4)
    - Revolutionary parties [Partiia Narodnoi Voli] (Box-folder 6: 5)
      Translations of articles and declarations relating to the Narodnaia Volia and other nineteenth century Russian revolutionary parties, including the Partiia Sotsialistov-Revoliutsionerov.
    - Rossiisko-amerikanskaia kompaniia [Rossiisko-amerikanskaia kompaniia; Ts Russia R967], circa 1700-1860 (Box-folder 6: 6)
      Laws made by the Russian government to regulate settlements established by the Russian-American Company on the Pacific coast of North America.
    - Russo-Japanese War. Clippings from the U.S. press, principally in San Francisco, 1904-1905
      - 1903-1905 (Box-folder 6: 7)
      - 1904
        - May (Box-folder 6: 8)
        - June (Box-folder 7: 1)
        - July (Box-folder 7: 2)
        - August (Box-folder 7: 3)
        - October (Box-folder 8: 1)
        - November (Box-folder 8: 2)
        - December (Box-folder 8: 3)
      - 1905
        - January (Box-folder 8: 4)
        - February (Box-folder 9: 1)
        - March (Box-folder 9: 2)
        - May (Box-folder 9: 3)
        - June (Box-folder 10: 1)
        - July (Box-folder 10: 2)
        - August (Box-folder 11: 1)
    - Russo-Romanian relations [Russo-Romanian Relations; Vw Romania R425], 1912 (Box-folder 11: 2)
      Report relating to conversations between an unnamed Russian Grand Duke and a number of Romanian political leaders regarding Romanian foreign policy and Russo-Romanian relations. Written by the Grand Duke and addressed to Tsar Nicolas II.
    - Miscellaneous [Russia – Miscellaneous] (Box-folder 11: 3-5)
      Writings, reports, pamphlets, leaflets, serial issues, clippings, and printed matter relating to various aspects of Russian culture and history. Includes financial records of the Tea Trade Society (V. Vysotsky and Company). Mainly in Russian.
  - Revolution and civil war
    - General
      - Posters, broadsides, and photocopies of newspaper and periodical articles, 1917-1921 (Box-folder 12: 1-6)
        Relates to the Russian civil war, as well as personnel records, notes, and printed matter, 1819-1924, relating to the Russian Revolution and founding congress of the Communist International. Includes instructions from the Secretariat of the Central Executive Committee of the VKP(b) to persons occupying the Kremlin, circa 1917-1918 [Russia – History – Revolution, 1917-1921]. Mainly in Russian.
      - Printed matter, 1917-1921 (Box-folder 12: 7)
      - Scrapbook of clippings relating to events in Russia, 1917-1921 (Box-folder 13: 1)
    - Agriculture, "Khlebnaia razverstka" (Bread procurement), data from Volyn' Region, 1921 April 14 (Box-folder 13: 2)
    - Atrocities. "The Photographic History of the Bolshevik Atrocities,", undated (Box-folder 13: 3)
    - Economic policy, "Kontsessionnaia politika bol'shevikov" (Concessionary Policy of the Bolsheviks), undated (Box-folder 13: 4)
    - Poetry. Guilbeaux, Henri, Kraskreml, Petersburg, 1922 (Box-folder 28: 3)
    - Posol'skaia incident [Posolskaya incident; Ms DK766 P854], 1920 (Box-folder 13: 5)
      Transcripts of testimony, summaries of conferences, declarations, and notes relating to the capture of the armored train of Ataman Grigirii Semenov, White Russian military leader, by the U.S. 27th Infantry Regiment at Posolskaia, Siberia, and to alleged atrocities committed by the troops of Ataman Semenov.
    - Post World War I reconstruction. Memorandum by L. Pushchin, undated (Box-folder 13: 6)
    - Press – Arkhangel'sk, 1918-1919 (Box-folder 13: 7)
      Translated extracts from newspaper articles relating to the Russian civil war. Translated from Arkhangel'sk newspaper.
    - Siberia, 1920 (Box-folder 13: 8)
      Orders, memoranda, and correspondence relating to the "icy march" campaign of V. Kappel', White Russian army general, in Siberia during the Russian civil war. In Russian.
    - Stepno-Badzheiskaya Volost', 1919 (Box-folder 13: 9)
      Memoranda and reports relating to the gathering of the harvest that was abandoned by the inhabitants of the Stepno-Badzheiskyi District in 1919. In Russian.
    - Treaties
      - "Anglo-Russkoe Soglashenie Podpisannoe 16-go Marta 1921 g." (Box-folder 13: 10)
      - "Dogovor R.S.F.S.R. s Persiei,", 1921 February 26 (Box-folder 13: 11)
    - Tsentral'noe Biuro po Obsluzhivaniiu Inostrantsev v Moskve pri Narodnom Komissariate po Inostrannym Delam. Beethoven concert program, 1921 December 11 (Box-folder 13: 12)
    - Volunteer Army. "The Volunteer Army of Alekseev and Denikin," by Prince P. M. Volkonskii, 1914 November (Box-folder 26: 12)
    - Vrangel' Government. Decrees relating primarily to land reform, 1920 (Box-folder 13: 13)
    - Vserossiiskii tsentral'nyi ispolnitel'nyi komitet. Tsentral'naia komissiia pomoshchi golodaiushchim
      - Bulletin, 1921 August - 1922 February/April (Box-folder 13: 14)
      - Leaflets, 1921 (Box-folder 13: 15)
    - Vserossiiskii s'ezd Sovetov, 9th, Moscow, Poriadok dnia, 1921 (Box-folder 13: 16)
    - Vysshii sovet narodnogo khoziaistva. Komitet po vneshnei torgovle. "K voprosu o plane kontsessii,", 1920 (Box-folder 13: 17)
  - Soviet Union
    - General
      - Bretscher, Will, Russia by Twilight. Pall Mall Features, Ltd., London, 1956 (Box-folder 13: 18)
      - Institute for the Study of the USSR Bulletin (Munich), nos. 11, 12, 1957 (Box-folder 13: 19)
      - Pacific Weekly, 1935 July - 1936 May 1 (Box-folder 13: 20)
        Photocopies of eight issues containing articles on the Soviet Union by Robert Marriman, commander of the Lincoln Battalion during its first battle in the Spanish civil war in February 1937.
      - Problems of the Peoples of the USSR (Munich)
        - No. 3, no. 7; nos. 11-12, 1959; 1961 (Box-folder 13: 21)
        - No. 16, no. 18, 1962, 1963 (Box-folder 13: 22)
      - Scrapbook of clippings relating to events in the Soviet Union, 1917-1936 (Box-folder 14: 1)
    - Agriculture and farming, 1959 (Box-folder 14: 2)
      Reports issued by the U.S. Department of Agriculture relating to Soviet agriculture and farming.
    - American engineers, 1929-1939
      Correspondence, writings, articles, and answers to questionnaires relating to economic conditions, ages, housing, living costs, and relations with Russian administrative personnel, by American engineers in Russia.
      - Card index information on American engineers in Russia (Box-folder 18: 1)
      - Correspondence
        - Aitkenhead, William C., 1934, 1936 (Box-folder 18: 2)
        - Alt, Harold, 1933 (Box-folder 18: 3)
        - Amtorg Trading Corporation, 1934 (Box-folder 18: 4)
        - Anderson, L. D., 1934 (Box-folder 18: 5)
        - Angst, H. H., 1934 (Box-folder 18: 6)
        - The Architectural Forum, 1934 (Box-folder 18: 7)
        - Arnott, Charles E., 1934 (Box-folder 18: 8)
        - Banks, Leon M., 1933-1934 (Box-folder 18: 9)
        - Bemis, O. M., 1934-1935 (Box-folder 18: 10)
        - Bendt, J. P., 1934 (Box-folder 18: 11)
        - Bennett, T. W., 1934 (Box-folder 18: 12)
        - Bone, Albert J., 1934 (Box-folder 18: 13)
        - Bubb, John B., 1935 (Box-folder 18: 14)
        - Budd, Ralph, 1933-1935 (Box-folder 18: 15)
        - Bunting, M. H., 1934-1936 (Box-folder 18: 16)
        - Burrell, G. A., 1933 (Box-folder 18: 17)
        - Butterworth, Charles, 1933 (Box-folder 18: 18)
        - Cady, C. R., 1934-1935 (Box-folder 18: 19)
        - Calder, John K., 1936 (Box-folder 18: 20)
        - Campbell, Thomas D., 1933 (Box-folder 18: 21)
        - Carmody, John M., 1933 (Box-folder 18: 22)
        - Chapman, Charles J., 1934 (Box-folder 18: 23)
        - Chase, Frank D., 1934 (Box-folder 18: 24)
        - Chase, Julian, 1933 (Box-folder 18: 25)
        - Clark, Wallace, 1934 (Box-folder 18: 26)
        - Clements, George L., 1934 (Box-folder 18: 27)
        - Clemmitt, Willis B., 1933-1935 (Box-folder 18: 28)
        - Collester, E. H., 1934 (Box-folder 18: 29)
        - Cook, Paul R., 1935-1936 (Box-folder 18: 30)
        - Cooper, D. P., 1934 (Box-folder 18: 31)
        - Cooper, Hugh L., 1934-1935 (Box-folder 18: 32)
        - Craggs, Clyde, 1933 (Box-folder 18: 33)
        - Crocker, Stuart M., 1934 (Box-folder 18: 34)
        - Crofoot, A. B., 1934 (Box-folder 18: 35)
        - Cullity, E. R., 1934 (Box-folder 18: 36)
        - Derby, R. M., 1933-1934 (Box-folder 18: 37)
        - Dickinson, E. S., 1934 (Box-folder 18: 38)
        - Dixon, W. F., 1934 (Box-folder 18: 39)
        - Donaldson, K. H., 1934-1935 (Box-folder 18: 40)
        - Draper, Robert M., 1934 (Box-folder 18: 41)
        - Du Pont de Nemours & Co., 1934 (Box-folder 18: 42)
        - Everhard, E. P., 1933, 1935 (Box-folder 18: 43)
        - Ferguson, J. S., 1933-1934 (Box-folder 18: 44)
        - Foos, I. D., 1933 (Box-folder 18: 45)
        - Forester, D. M., 1935 (Box-folder 18: 46)
        - Foss, Fedor F., 1933, 1935-1937 (Box-folder 18: 47)
        - Foster, George K., 1934 (Box-folder 18: 48)
        - Fox, Gordon, 1933-1935 (Box-folder 18: 49)
        - Fulmer, O. K., 1934 (Box-folder 18: 50)
        - Garcia, John A., 1934, 1936 (Box-folder 18: 51)
        - Garrett, Nona, 1933 (Box-folder 18: 52)
        - Gibbs, H. D., 1934 (Box-folder 18: 53)
        - Gill, C. A., 1934 (Box-folder 18: 54)
        - Gillis, J. H., 1936-1937 (Box-folder 18: 55)
        - Gorton, W. L., 1934, 1936 (Box-folder 18: 56)
        - Grady, William H., 1933 (Box-folder 18: 57)
        - Growcott, G., 1934 (Box-folder 18: 58)
        - Hahn, Albert W., 1934-1935 (Box-folder 19: 1)
        - Hallock, F. B., 1934 (Box-folder 19: 2)
        - Harris, Frederic R., 1933-1934 (Box-folder 19: 3)
        - Harry, Charles M., 1935 (Box-folder 19: 4)
        - Haven, William A., 1933, 1935 (Box-folder 19: 5)
        - Herrmann, F. C., 1934 (Box-folder 19: 6)
        - Hoen, Richard D., 1935 (Box-folder 19: 7)
        - Hoffman, Arnold, 1933 (Box-folder 19: 8)
        - Hollister, S. E., 1934 (Box-folder 19: 9)
        - Holmboe, T. R., 1934 (Box-folder 19: 10)
        - Hunter, Harry G., 1934 (Box-folder 19: 11)
        - James H. Pierce and Co., 1933-1934 (Box-folder 19: 12)
        - Jermain, George D., 1934-1935 (Box-folder 19: 13)
        - Kahn, Albert, 1933 (Box-folder 19: 14)
        - The Koppers Construction Co., 1934 (Box-folder 19: 15)
        - Krejci, M. W., 1934-1939 (Box-folder 19: 16)
        - Krumb, Henry, 1933 (Box-folder 19: 17)
        - Lawry, Raymond G., 1934 (Box-folder 19: 18)
        - Lea, John, 1934 (Box-folder 19: 19)
        - Lee, Marvin, 1933 (Box-folder 19: 20)
        - MacDonald, H. J. C., 1934 (Box-folder 19: 21)
        - McKee, Arthur G., 1934 (Box-folder 19: 22)
        - Mayer, Lucius W., 1933-1934 (Box-folder 19: 23)
        - Midwest Rubber Reclaiming Co., 1934 (Box-folder 19: 24)
        - Miller, George L., 1933 (Box-folder 19: 25)
        - Morgan, T. A., 1935 (Box-folder 19: 26)
        - Oglebay Norton and Co., 1934 (Box-folder 19: 27)
        - Olberg, C. R., 1934 (Box-folder 19: 28)
        - Orr, W. S., 1933 (Box-folder 19: 29)
        - Oxnam, T. H., 1934-1935 (Box-folder 19: 30)
        - Peters, W. A., Jr., 1934 (Box-folder 19: 31)
        - Pickering, J. C., 1933 (Box-folder 19: 32)
        - Polakov, Walter N., 1934 (Box-folder 19: 33)
        - Pope, Frederick, 1934 (Box-folder 19: 34)
        - Prommel, H. W. C., 1934 (Box-folder 19: 35)
        - Prouty, Roswell W., 1934 (Box-folder 19: 36)
        - Pullus, Nicholas J., 1933 (Box-folder 19: 37)
        - Radio Corporation of America, 1934 (Box-folder 19: 38)
        - Reynders, John V. W., 1933 (Box-folder 19: 39)
        - Rickard, Edgar, 1933 (Box-folder 19: 40)
        - Riddell, Guy C., 1933 (Box-folder 19: 41)
        - Rogers, K. A., 1934-1935 (Box-folder 19: 42)
        - Rosenfield, Isadore, 1934 (Box-folder 19: 43)
        - Rukeyser, Walter A., 1934 (Box-folder 19: 44)
        - Scrymgeour, George K., 1934 (Box-folder 19: 45)
        - Seabrook, C. F., 1935 (Box-folder 19: 46)
        - Seabury, George T., 1934 (Box-folder 19: 47)
        - The Seiberling Rubber Company, 1934 (Box-folder 19: 48)
        - Shaffner, Charles N., 1933 (Box-folder 19: 49)
        - Sherover, M. M., 1933-1934 (Box-folder 19: 50)
        - Shipley, W. S., 1934 (Box-folder 19: 51)
        - Sibley, Robert, 1933 (Box-folder 19: 52)
        - Skvirsky, Boris E., 1934 (Box-folder 19: 53)
        - Standard Oil Company of New York, 1934 (Box-folder 19: 54)
        - Stanton, William L., 1934 (Box-folder 19: 55)
        - Stuart, Charles E., 1933-1934 (Box-folder 19: 56)
        - Stuck, R. W., 1934-1935 (Box-folder 19: 57)
        - Sullivan Machinery Company, 1934 (Box-folder 19: 58)
        - Swanson, Arthur, 1933-1934 (Box-folder 19: 59)
        - Thomson, Joseph L., 1933 (Box-folder 19: 60)
        - Torpen, B. E., 1933 (Box-folder 19: 61)
        - Trecartin, H. S., 1933-1934 (Box-folder 19: 62)
        - Uhler, F. W., 1934 (Box-folder 19: 63)
        - Wasserman, William S., 1933 (Box-folder 19: 64)
        - Westvaco Chlorine Products, Inc., 1934 (Box-folder 19: 65)
        - Wood, W. A., 1934 (Box-folder 19: 66)
        - Worsham, A. H., 1934 (Box-folder 19: 67)
        - Young, Owen D., 1933 (Box-folder 19: 68)
      - Form letters (Box-folder 19: 69)
      - Lists
        - Articles published by American engineers (Box-folder 19: 70)
        - Engineers (Box-folder 19: 71)
        - Firms having contracts with the U.S.S.R. (Box-folder 19: 72)
        - Persons familiar with conditions in Russia (Box-folder 19: 73)
        - Technical assistance contracts (Box-folder 19: 74)
      - Questionnaire
        - General (Box-folder 19: 75)
        - Responses by
          - Aitkenhead, W. C. (Box-folder 19: 76)
          - Allen and Garcia Co. (Box-folder 19: 77)
          - Alt, Harold L. (Box-folder 19: 78)
          - Anderson, L. D. (Box-folder 19: 79)
          - Angst, H. H. (Box-folder 19: 80)
          - Banks, Leon M. (Box-folder 19: 81)
          - Bemis, O. M. (Box-folder 19: 82)
          - Bendt, J. P. (Box-folder 19: 83)
          - Bone, Albert J. (Box-folder 19: 84)
          - Brown, L. R. (Box-folder 19: 85)
          - Bubb, John B. (Box-folder 20: 1)
          - Butterworth, Charles (Box-folder 20: 2)
          - Cady, C. R. (Box-folder 20: 3)
          - Clemmitt, Willis B. (Box-folder 20: 4)
          - Collester, E. H. (Box-folder 20: 5)
          - Cullity, E. R. (Box-folder 20: 6)
          - Dickinson, E. S. (Box-folder 20: 7)
          - Donaldson, K. H. (Box-folder 20: 8)
          - Draper, Robert M. (Box-folder 20: 9)
          - Everhard, E. P. (Box-folder 20: 10)
          - Ferguson, J. S. (Box-folder 20: 11)
          - Forester, D. M. (Box-folder 20: 12)
          - Foss, Fedor F. (Box-folder 20: 13)
          - Foster, George K. (Box-folder 20: 14)
          - Fox, Gordon (Box-folder 20: 15)
          - Fulmer, O. Kline (Box-folder 20: 16)
          - Garcia, John A. (Box-folder 20: 17)
          - Gill, C. A. (Box-folder 20: 18)
          - Gillis, Julius H. (Box-folder 20: 19)
          - Growcott, G. (Box-folder 20: 20)
          - Hahn, Albert W. (Box-folder 20: 21)
          - Harris, Frederick R. (Box-folder 20: 22)
          - Harry, Charles M. (Box-folder 20: 23)
          - Hebley, H. F. (Box-folder 20: 24)
          - Holmboe, T. R. (Box-folder 20: 25)
          - Hunter, Harry G. (Box-folder 20: 26)
          - Jenney, J. K. (Box-folder 20: 27)
          - Jermain, G. D. (Box-folder 20: 28)
          - Krejci, Milo W. (Box-folder 20: 29)
          - Lawry, Raymond G. (Box-folder 20: 30)
          - Lea, John (Box-folder 20: 31)
          - McKee, Arthur G. (Box-folder 20: 32)